# **ALAN SANTOS**

# Software Engineer

Cubatão, Brazil

+55 13 98862-1433 | alansantos04@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alan-santos-profile | https://github.com/AlanEditor

I am actively pursuing opportunities as a Laravel and Vue.js Developer to contribute my expertise to dynamic projects. I bring a proactive approach, a genuine passion for programming, and a dedication to delivering optimal user experiences. With a focus on propelling the success of one of the industry's most promising companies, I am well-equipped to tackle diverse technical challenges. My proficiency in current technologies, particularly Laravel and Vue.js, and my exploration of the nuances of development in these frameworks for web applications uniquely position me to make significant contributions to your team.

# **Professional Experience**

## **Mid-Level Backend Engineer**

Ensinio | São Paulo, Brazil (Remote) | May 2023 - Present

- Developed Restful APIs using Laravel and MySQL.
- Applied and reviewed best practices, particularly SOLID principles.
- Implemented automated testing.
- Successfully reduced processing time in database gueries by 50%.
- Executed data migration for the new platform version.
- Created unique features to enhance customer experience.

#### **Junior Backend Engineer**

iPORTO | Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil (Remote) | Jun. 2022 – Jun. 2023

- Developed Restful APIs using Laravel, MySQL, Docker, and MongoDB.
- Restructured code architecture using best practices.
- Implemented automated testing.
- Created functionalities for clients.
- Generated reports for CRM management.
- Reduced legacy code.
- Facilitated source code maintenance using established patterns.
- Developed unique features to enhance customer experience and reports using obtained data.
- Achieved a 25% increase in revenue with the newly developed features.

## **System Analist**

Sonda IT | São Paulo, Brazil (Remote) | Jan. 2022 – Jun. 2023

- Providing user support services.
- Developing initiatives for system migrations.
- Implementing automated testing.
- Developed Rest API with Laravel and MySQL.

### **System Analist**

Fênix | São Paulo, Brazil (Remote) | Nov. 2021 – Jan. 2022

- Developing the internal monitoring system using Laravel and MySQL.
- Configuring the internal network and managing external links.

## **Education**

## **Software Engineering**

Focus College | Postgraduate | 2023

### **System Analysis and Development**

Santa Cecília University | Technologist | 2021 – 2023

# Languages

- English Fluent
- Spanish Advanced
- Portuguese Native

# **Project**

# **E-learning Platform - Federation of Marian Congregations of Santos**

Vice President and Software Engineer

In this role, I spearheaded efforts in developing a distance learning platform (E-learning) tailored specifically for the Marian Congregations of Santos. Leading a team using Laravel and Vue technologies, our commitment is to create an innovative and efficient technological solution.